A Guide to the Milka T. Bliznakov Papers and Architectural Drawings, 1946-2010
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1926, 1960-2009; Box
  - Subseries g. Reference Files, 1926-1998
    - Women and Architecture, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Change of Profession?, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - White Collar, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Women Artists: Female Experience in Art, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "Issues of Historical Preservation in Central Europe and Russia" Conference Proceedings, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Civil Engineers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Soviet Union Vol. 3 Part 2 1976 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Soviet Union Vol. 5 Part 2 1978 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Soviet Union Vol. 7 Parts 1-2 1980 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Studies Made on Six World Reports at the Request of U.N.E.S.C.O. (1975) (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Bulgarian Architecture, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Historic Wisconsin Architecture, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Building Moscow, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Seventh Congress of International Union of Architects (1963) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Places & Settings, 1972; This file contains a publication called "Places & Settings" on architecture, landscape, and interior design. (Box 7, Folder 16-17, 19)
  - Subseries h. Portfolio, 1965, 1970, 1972, 1974, 1975; This file contains a compilation of Milka Bliznakov's architectural projects. The documents were originally kept in a cowhide briefcase. The portfolio remains in its original order and contains sketches, floor plans, landscaping plans, etc.; Box (Box 14)
  - Subseries i. Exhibition Posters, 1977-1980
    - Anna Luja Paun Exhibition Poster, n.d.
    - Dallas Musuem of Fine Arts Exhibition Poster, 1980
    - Society of Architectural Historians: "Soviet Avant-Garde Art & Architecture in the 1920s", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Series III. Faculty Papers, 1974-1996
  This series consists of faculy papers such as administrative materials, course materials, research notes, and reference files. While most of the series consists of materials from Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, there are some materials from the University of Colombia. The content in this series expands from 1974-1996.
  - Subseries a. Administrative, 1980-1996
    - Title IX, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Tour to Moscow-Leningrad (October-Novemner 1989) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - College of Architecture and Urban Studies Journal, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Regarding LAR Studie, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Positions Available (1996) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subseries b. Course Materials, 1974
    - Syllabus, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - History of Architecture: Vienna, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - History of Architecture: Greek and Roman (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - History of Architecture: Early Christian and Byzantine (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - History of Architecture: Renaissance, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - History of Architecture: Egypt, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Egyptian and Minoan-Mycenaean (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Subseries c. Reference Files, 1991
    - Architecture Team Places Nationally, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Series IV. Major Projects, 1946-1983
  This series consists of Milka Bliznakov's architectural records for various residential projects. Content in this series extends from 1946-1983.
  - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive Project Records, n.d.
    - Milka Bliznakov's Residence Files, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Photos of Milka's House, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #1-2 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 8)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #3-5 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #6-8 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #9-11 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #12-14 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 12)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, #14-18 of 18, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, interior detail drawings (Box 15)
    - 2813 Tall Oaks Drive, additions and renovations after 1987 (Box 16)
  - Barranco Residence Project Records, 1981-1983
    - Barranco Residence Files, 1981-1983; This file contains advertisements, business correspondence, and other documents regarding the Barranco residence. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Barranco Residence Drawings, 1981-1983; This file contains 16 sketches and plans for the Barranco residence. In addition, it contains preliminary landscape master plan concept. (Folder 1)
    - Barranco Residence Pool Plans, 1981-1983 (Folder 2)
    - Interior Design Plans, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 518 Buckeye Trail Project Records, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - 518 Buckeye Trail Files, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 2009 Bergman, 1946-1973
    - Warranty Deeds Goode - 2009 Bergman, 1946-1947, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - House Remodeling: 2009 Bergman Street - Austin, Texas, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - 2009 Bergman Street - Austin, Texas, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Phillips/Karazim Residence
    - Phillips/Karazim Drawings, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Murphy's Residence, n.d.; This file includes remodeling plans for the Murphy residence. (Box 7, Folder 21, Box 17)
  - Anderson & Associates Inc. - Blacksburg, Virginia, This file contains drawings for a residential house in Blacksburg, Virginia. It includes landscapes, elevations, gazebo plans, and deck plans. (Folder 6, Box 18)
  - Tony's House, n.d.; This file contains architectural drawings on transparent paper. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Series V. Art & Artifacts, n.d., 2007
  This series consists of art and artifacts donated to the Milka Bliznakov collection. Within this series, there is a metal file cabinet containing contact information. The cabinet contains contact information of Milka's friends, family, acquaintances, and colleagues. In addition, there are two large, framed awards and a t-shaped wooden utensil for drawing purposes. One of the awards is dated in 2007, but the other awards are not dated.
  - T-Square, n.d.
  - A Gift to Milka Bliznakov from the College of Architecture and Urban Studies
  - Diversity Award, 2007
  - Milka's Filing Cabinet, n.d.; This filing cabinet consists of contact information. The left drawer, which includes IAWA board members, is organized by last name. The right drawer is organized by region. It includes contacts from Iceland, Great Britain, West Germany, Switzerland, France, Portugal, Spain, and South America.
  - Posters (Box 30, Box 31)
- Series VI. Additions
  - Subseries a. Reference Files
    - House of the Government of Georgia, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - To Erect a Monument in Memory of the Polar Trek "Chelyuskina", 1934 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Windows on the Russian Past: Essays on Soviet Historiography Since Stalin (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Second World Congress on Soviet and East European Studies: The Emigre Artists in the West (USA) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Cultural Life in the USSR (1928-1941), 1978 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - 50th Anniversary of the Electrification Plan and the Development of Architecture Hydropower Facilities (1970) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Soviet Art Studies, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Prominent Architect, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Architect N.Y. Kolli, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Architect Pantelimon Golosov, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Kondrat Pantelimon Golosov, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Vladimir Fedrovich Krinski, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Ivan Alexandrovich Fomin, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - A.P. Ivanitski, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Architect Lydia Constantinovna Komarova, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Mentoring Nechemnozemyu, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - In Context Modernity and History, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - P.A. Golosov, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Architect Victor Alexandrovich Vesni, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Construction Industry, 1924-1931 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Blokhin Layout of Residential Quarters of the City Sogu, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Architecture and Urban Design, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Socialist City and its Architecture, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Socialist Kharov, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Lived in the House of the Leningrad Council, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Architecture and Technology, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Sanatorium Construction in the USSR, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - May the Lessons of Architecture Exhibitions Creative Discussions in the Union of Soviet Architects, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Interior Problem, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Oven - On Proletarian Architecture, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - From Work, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Fur House Design Competition People's Commissariat in Moscow, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - What Architecture We Need, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Architecture in the USSR: Systematic Index of Articles and Materials for 5 Years, July 1933-June 1938 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Department Store and Residential Building on the Street of Dzerzhinsky, Moscow, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Book House Orlikov, Architect B.M. Velikovski, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Creative Discussion of the Soviet Union Architects, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Practice: Power Architecture, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Architecture in the USSR, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Igor V. Ryazantsev: Soviet Exhibition Ensemble, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - At the Front of the Iranian Architecture, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Construction and Architecture, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Construction of Moscow, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Moscow Building: Labor Communes Kostino Draft Plan, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - AVTOSTROY-Socialist City, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Moscow Building: City Recreation and the Socialist Way of Life, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 48)
    - Art Volume 4, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 49)
    - Architecture and Construction: Authority for Architecture Committee of the SNK, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Architecture and Construction: Master of Architecture in the First Year of the Fourth Five-Year Plan Stalin, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Architecture and Construction of the Country Life, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Architecture and Construction: Master of Architecture in the First Year of Post-War Stalinist Five-Year Plan, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Architecture and Construction: The Committee for Architecture at the USSR Council of Ministers, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Building in Moscow, 1924-1933 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Building in Moscow, 1927-1928 (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - A. Mikhaylov: Of the Art of the Reconstruction Period, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - The Issue of Soviet Art and Architecture, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - International Contemporary Art, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Ezhdik Society of Architectural Artists, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Alexei V. Babichev: Artist, Theorist, Teacher, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Relationship of Russian and Soviet Art and German Art Culture (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - History of Russian Art, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Modern Architecture Articles and Notes, 1926-1930 (Box 22, Folder 6, Folder 7)
    - Soviet Architecture in Transformation by Paul Willen, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Soviet Art, 1926-1929 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - L'Architecture Vivante, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Freeman Voices of October, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Art Under a Dictatorship, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Russian Modernism: Culture and Avant-Garde (1900-1930), 1976 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - OSA + Constructivism, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Soviet Political Poster 1917-1920 by M.F. Savelov, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - MAZAEY, Concept - "Manufacturing Art", 1975 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Culture and Style - J. Joffe, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Architecture in the USSR, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Soviet Architecture, 1961, 1964, 1965, 1967, 1969, 1972, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Art in the USSR and the Tasks Dispute Artists, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Soviet Architecture, 1933- (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Yearbook MAO No, 5, 1928 and Architecture No. 1-2, 1923, 1923, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Velmir Khlebnikov - Snake Train, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Aleksei Gan - Constructivism, 1920 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Almanac Proletcult - Moscow, 1925 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Red Student, 1923 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Artistic Work in 1919, St. Petersburg (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Firebird, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Art Journal Russian Academy of Artistic Sciences, 1923, 1925, 1927 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - On the Paths of Art Literature of Fact, 1926, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Horn, 1919 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Proletarian Culture, 1918-1919 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Revolution and Culture Publication Pravda Newspaper, 1924, 1927, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Printing and Revolution, 1921-1930 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - LEF, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 9, Folder 10)
    - New LEF, 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Soviet Architecture, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 12, Folder 13)
    - Institute of History and Art, Ministry of Culture in the USSR: Questions of Soviet Art and Architecture (1973) (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Architectural Creativity of the USSR, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - R.Ia. Rhiger, Architecture Drawing Stations, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - K.K. Lagustin Architectural Image of Soviet Public Figures, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - V.E. Bykov and Dr. J. Cornfield: Architecture Business Culture Club, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Cooperative Housing, 1922-1923 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - LEF, 1924 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Architecture and Art Workshops: Collection of Studio Art Izhsia Islands, Leningrad, 1927, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Artistic Work, 1919 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Science and Technology, No. 23 (376): 8th Year Edition, 1930-04-25 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Art No. 1, Moscow-Leningrad, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - The Arts Committee of the Body, 1919 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Art and Weight, No. 12, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Y. Tugendhold, Art of the October Era, Leningrad, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - N. Tutin, Tatlin, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Composition, Stroliner, B.T.i. Yushkevich, PS Art and Literature in Marx: Light Lighting - Moscow, 1925 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Russian Art, 1923 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Artistic Life, 1919 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Art Gazette, Moscow and Gazette Artists, Moscow, Brigade Artists, No. 7, Moscow, 1921, 1922, 1931 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Architecture and Construction in Moscow, 1955-1958 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Problems of the History of Soviet Architecture, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Settling System Urals, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - V.V. Pokshishevskiy and G.M. Larro, Moscow, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Frunze City Guide and Novosibirsk, 1963, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Balkhash: Planning and Development, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1935, 1936, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - V.O.K.S. Published by the Soviet Union Society for Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries No. 1-3, January-February, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - M. Zeitlin, Moscow Plan Bibliography on Socialist Cities, 1972, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Konstantin Umanski: New Art in Russia, 1914-1919 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Gallery Deiemen & Co: First Russian Art Exhibit, Berlin 1922, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Architectural Design and Construction, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Catalogs: Paris, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs: New York, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Catalogs: Bicnnale, Nurenberg, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Russian Architecture and Town Planning, 1917-1933 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 11, Folder 12)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 13, Folder 14)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 15, Folder 16)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 17, Folder 18)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 19, Folder 20)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 21, Folder 22)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1937-1941 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1935-1937 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - German Editorials on Architecture, 1924-1925 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1946-1947 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1951-1952, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1953 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1955, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1967-1969 (Box 27, Folder 1, Folder 2)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1972, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Architecture of the USSR, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Bulgarian Engineering Company Architects: Anniversary Publication/Collection Marking 1000 Years since Simeon Era and 50 Years since Bulgarian Liberation, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - BIAD: Scientific Congress, 1933-1941 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Journal of Bulgarian Engineering Company Architects, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - BIAD: Scientific Congress, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - BIAD: Scientific Congress, 1931 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - BIAD: Scientific Congress, 1930 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - BIAD: Scientific Congress, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Architecture after 1989, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Architecture in the USSR: Bulgarian Architects, 1964, 1966, 1978, 1980, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Architecture Part V, 1973, 1975, 1977, 1984, 1989, 1990, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Theory on Social Realism, 1963, 1971-1972, 1977-1978, 1980-1981, 1986, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Bulgarian Architects after 1945, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Varna before 1949, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Architecture in the Age of Bulgarian Revival, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - The Architecture of the Bulgarian Revival-George Kozhuharov, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Balkan City: XV-XIX Century-Nikolai Todorov, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Planning of Settlements in Bulgarian Liberation Until September 9th, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Synagogues of Europe-Carol Herselle Krinsky, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Architecture Before 1879, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - A History of Ottoman Architecture-Godrey Goodwin, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Guidebooks, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - National Tradition and New Regionalism (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Modern Architecture-General (1920s-1930s), n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Koprivshtitsa-Historic Town in Bulgaria, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Sofia, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Urbanization after 1944, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Various, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - BIAD, 1889, 1894, 1895, 1905 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - BIAD, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - BIAD, 1906, 1907, 1910 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - BIAD, 1923, 1924, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - BIAD, 1926, 1927, 1928 (Box 24, Folder 12)